MIKE GOLD

Full stack & Mobile Developer

@ mikegold4060@gmail.com

? Tengah, Singapore

SUMMARY

Highly experienced and motivated Full Stack Developer with over 8 years of experience in web development, programming, and software development. Have a strong background in web technologies and a strong understanding of React.js, Next.js, Java, Kotlin, Flutter, React Native, JavaScript, and other programming languages. Also have highly knowledge in database management, agile management, web applications, and mobile development. An excellent problem solver who is able to quickly identify and fix issues with code, as well as build and maintain software projects. Highly organized and detail-oriented, and is able to work independently or as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

2020 - 2023

Ennis, County Clare, Ireland

Senior Full Stack & Mobile Developer

KleverApps Co!

- · Developed and maintained 10+ front-ends focused on user experience.
- · Wrote front-end code, back-end code, integrated 4+ with frameworks and APIs, and utilized multiple CLI tools and configuration GUI's. Created and updated 2 websites with a focus on creating an exceptional user experience.
- Utilized and implemented 5+ attractive, responsive, and mobile-friendly website contexts and elements.
- · Created informative and effective documentation, reports, and inline comments on 100% of code/work accomplished.
- Developed and maintained mobile applications resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement and a 30% increase in app downloads.
- · Implemented new features and functionality for Android applications using Java and Kotlin languages.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop mobile applications that met business requirements.

2019 - 2020

Paris, France

Entry-Level Full Stack & Mobile Developer

HCL Technologies

- · Built 30+ custom interfaces using the Periodic API.
- · Replaced 1 full-time web developer under part-time employment achieving a productivity gain of over 60% as measured by working hours.
- Implemented 14 new features as defined and scoped by a product team of 12 Collaborated with 2 different development teams on 4 new project designs and feature improvements.
- · Diagnosed and fixed report functionality issues by troubleshooting.
- · Worked with 8+ teams to build web-based tools to facilitate their development lifecycle.

2017 - 2019

High Wycombe, UK

Junior Full Stack & Mobile Developer

Bugtreat Technologies

- · Implemented rich user experiences by creating 30+ new features utilizing HTML/JS/CSS.
- Developed and maintained 20+ REST APIs writing documentation using OpenAPI specifications.
- · Collaborated with 2 engineering teams on domain, design, and code testing for 8+ projects.
- · Followed industry best practices, company best practices, and learned 3 new technologies.
- Developed and improved existing applications for both tablets and mobile phones using Android SDK.
- · Developed efficient and reliable code using Java, XML, and Android Studio.
- · Integrated mobile applications with web services such as REST and JSON.

EDUCATION

09/2013 - 01/2017

Athens, OH

B.D. in Computer Science
Computer Science University of Ohio
GPA 3.8 / 3.9

SKILLS

Client-Side

HTML CSS JS React Vue Next TypeScript Bootstrap

Server-side

NodeJS Laravel Redis MongoDB MySQL

Mobile

Android iOS Java Kotlin Flutter React Native Swift

Others

Agile Scrum Git